Pierre Lecomte du Nouy papers, 1883-1972 (bulk 1917-1949)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Series VII: Scrapbooks and manuscripts, 1920-1972
  - Manuscripts: La Température Critique du Serum, includes manuscript, typescript, figures, and letters of acknowledgment. 1936-1945 (Box 28, Folder 1-5)
  - Manuscripts: Le Temps et la Vie ( Biological Time), includes typescript, figures, and letters of acknowledgment. 1936 (Box 28, Folder 6-7)
  - Manuscripts: Exposé des Travaux, includes manuscript, printed work, and letters of acknowledgment. 1937 (Box 29, Folder 1-3)
  - Manuscripts: L'Homme Devant La Science, includes manuscript, galley proofs, and letters of acknowledgment. 1936-1940 (Box 30, Folder 1-3)
  - Manuscripts: Road to Reason, includes galley proofs and general correspondence. 1947-1949 (Box 30, Folder 4-5)
  - Scrapbook, clippings concerning L'Homme Devant la Science. 1939 (Box 31)
  - Scrapbook, clippings concerning Road to Reason. 1948-1949 (Box 32)
  - Manuscripts: L'Avenir de L'Esprit, includes galley proofs, manuscript, typescript, notes to the Preface of the American edition, letters of acknowledgment to the French and American editions, and scrapbook of clippings concerning L'Avenir de L'Esprit and La Dignité Humaine. 1941-1950 (Box 33)
  - Manuscripts: La Dignité Humaine, includes manuscript, galley proofs, introduction and first chapter of English translation, and correspondence relating to the American edition. 1943-1950 (Box 34)
  - Manuscripts: Human Destiny, manuscript. 1945 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Manuscripts: Human Destiny, typescript. 1947 (Box 35, Folder 2-3)
  - Manuscripts: Human Destiny, correspondence with Longmans, Green (Isabel Paterson, editor). 1946 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Manuscripts: Human Destiny, correspondence. January-March 1947 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Manuscripts: Human Destiny, correspondence. April-December 1947 (Box 36, Folder 1-6)
  - Manuscripts: Human Destiny, correspondence. January 1948-1952 (Box 37, Folder 1-7)
  - Scrapbook: Human Destiny. 1947 (Box 38)
  - Scrapbook: Human Destiny. 1947-1950 (Box 39)
  - Scrapbook: Human Destiny. 1948-1949 (Box 40)
  - Scrapbook: Human Destiny. 1949-1950 (Box 41)
  - Scrapbook: Human Destiny. 1950-1951 (Box 42)
  - Scrapbook: Human Destiny. 1951-1952 (Box 43)
  - Scrapbook: Human Destiny. 1953-1958 (Box 44)
  - Scrapbook: Human Destiny. 1959-1969 (Box 45)
  - Scrapbook: The Road to Human Destiny. 1955-1960 (Box 46)
  - Scrapbook: articles about Piere Lecomte de Noüy. 1931-1970 (Box 47, Folder 1-5)
  - Scrapbook: Entre Savoir et Croire. 1964-1965 (Box 48)
  - Scrapbook, clippings concerning the life and career of Pierre Lecomte de Noüy. 1965-1972 (Box 49)
  - Scrapbook: Lecomte de Noüy Prize, clippings concerning the Pierre Lecomte du Noüy Prize: an international award for a philosophical scientific or biographical work written, or translated into French or English, which must give evidence of particular interest in the spiritual life of our time and in upholding the dignity of man. Awarded annually. 1953-1957 (Box 50)
- Series VIII: Oversize material, 1894-1945
  - Oversize material, includes diplomas, awards, certificates, photographs, family memorabilia and autograph book. (Box 51)
  - Oversize material, includes art work, scientific drawings, and articles about Pierre Lecomte de Noüy. 1894-1945 (Box 52)